JAMES KIMANI

Address · +254740736999 kimaniwaigi@gmail.com ·

https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-kimani-0b600472/

Senior Quality Construction Inspector/Supervisor specializing in Railway and Road Construction, with over 8 years of experience. Highly Qualified and Knowledgeable in the principles and standards of Civil Engineering Construction. Involved in several mega construction projects worth billions of Kenya shillings. Well-versed in several Civil Engineering Disciplines and Processes. Strong background in quality assuarance, project management and social relations.

EXPERIENCE

AUG 2021 - MARCH 2022

QUALITY CONTROL INSPECTOR, SOBETRA UGANDA LIMITED KENYA.

KONZA CITY TECHNOPOLIS PROJECT.

- 1. Supervision of road earthworks, Utility networks such as water supply, Irrigation, sewer, stormwater networks, ICT, Streetlight, medium voltage and low voltage networks and concrete structures undertaken by the construction team.
- 2. Raising, planning and organising for Quality Assurance Inspections by the Engineer's supervision team. ICM.
- 3. Ensuring the construction team onsite has all the Technical design specifications and drawings and are properly understood and inplemented.

AUG 2017 - MAY 2021

QUALITY CONTROL INSPECTOR, CSDI-APEC-EDON CONSORTIUM [CAEC]

SGR PROJECT, PHASE II

- 1. Supervision of quality subgrade embarkments earthworks and concrete structures undertaken by the contractor.
- 2. Implementation of design reviews and advising the contractor on efficient methods of carrying out certain tasks as directed by the Resident Engineer.
- 3. Conducting field density tests of embankment fills, qualifying of materials to be used for embankment construction as well as concrete tests.
- 4. Keeping daily and weekly progress reports of the amount and quality of works done, including the nature of site conditions and the weather.
- 5. Development and ensuring proper safety guidelines and measures are being observed in the site as stipulated in the laws of safety.
- 6. Communication and coordination of works as directed by the resident Engineer.
- 7. Signing work qualification sheets for the contractor to give approval for the works done on site, and enforcement of safety regulations.

CSDI-APEC-EDON CONSORTIUM, P.O. Box 3786, 00100, Nairobi.

MARCH 2015 - AUG 2017

QUALITY CONTROL INSPECTOR, TSDI-APEC-EDON CONSORTIUM [TAEC].

SGR PROJECT, PHASE I

- 1. Supervision of quality subgrade and embarkments earthworks, A section stretching 120KM in length.
- 2. Implementation of design reviews and advising the contractor on efficient methods of carrying out certain tasks as directed by the Resident Engineer.
- 3. Conducting field density tests of embankment fills, qualifying of materials to be used for embankment construction as well as concrete tests.
- 4. Keeping daily and weekly progress reports of the amount and quality of works done, including the nature of site conditions and the weather.
- 5. Development and ensuring proper safety guidelines and measures are being observed in the site as stipulated in the laws of safety.
- 6. Communication and coordination of works as directed by the resident Engineer.
- 7. Signing work qualification sheets for the contractor to give approval for the works done on site, and enforcement of safety regulations.

TSDI-APEC-EDON CONSORTIUM, P.O. Box 3786, 00100, Nairobi.

OCT 2014 - AUG 2015

SUPERVISOR, MYG ENGINEERING LTD.

- 1. Organization of all construction project activities and development of strategies in tackling building tasks.
- 2. Support and involvement in decision making with the directors for the achievement of goals of the company.
- 3. Actively involved in design and development of plans for different construction projects.

JUNE 2012 - AUG 2014

QUALITY CONTROL INSPECTOR, APEC CONSORTIUM.

LANGATA ROAD PROJECT. KWS TO BOMAS OF KENYA

- 1. Supervising quality construction works undertaken by the contractor.
- 2. Developing reports from daily reports and weekly reports received from Inspectors.
- 3. Planning and coordinating activities to be undertaken by site inspectors and ensuring proper conveying of data and communication as directed by the resident engineer.
- 4. Ensuring all designs and design reviews are properly understood and Implemented as directed by the Engineer.
- 5. Performing quality checks on materials to be used on site, in-conjunction with the lab assistants and signing quality approval sheets for the contractor.
- 6. Assisted in the preparation of monthly progress reports used for the development of EPC certificates.
- 7. Facilitated in the procurement of safety gear for all the staff, following the concern of safety and environmental issues.

APEC CONSORTIUM, P.O. Box 3786 – 00100, Nairobi Kenya.

JAN 2012 - MARCH 2012

CLERK, GANTT CONSTRUCTION LTD.

- 1. Developed bills of quantities.
- 2. Participated in the tendering processes.
- 3. Taking out of levels in survey works.
- 4. Preparing of work schedules
- 5. Collecting data of materials on site for testing
- 6. Clerical/Administration work of registering materials on site and record keeping

EDUCATION

2009 - 2011

DIPLOMA IN HIGHWAY ENGINEERING, KENYA INSTITUTE OF HIGHWAYS AND BUILDING TECHNOLOGY.

- 1. Principles of surveying
- 2. Highway design and construction
- 3. Design Structures
- 4. Building construction and costing
- 5. Material classification and tests
- 6. Measurements and Surveying.
- 7. Projects implementation skills and seminar
- 8. Research issues in measuring development goals
- 9. construction management
- 10. Architectural design and drawings.
- 11. Environmental and safety studies and research
- 12. Algebra Calculus and Matrices for statistics

2003 - 2007

KCSE, NDURURUMO HIGHSCHOOL.

[B PLAIN]

SKILLS

- Social skills and competences
- Technical competences
- Computer skills

- I have strong communication, ethical, social and observational skills. Acquired over 9 years' experience.
- Excellent in Quality control, Design, Survey, Project implementation and Supervision.
- Proficient in CAD applications, ArchiCAD, AutoCAD, PROKON AND PIRANESSI.
 Microsoft office applications such as word, Excel, PowerPoint etc.
- Adequate programming skills, Java script, python and html.

- Organisational skills and competences
- I am good in data organization and management, database update and maintenance, report writing, document typesetting and construction ingenuity.

ACTIVITIES

- I am a member of the Kenya Red cross society.
- Worked as a Vaccine Accountability Monitor under the Ministry of Health, During the Polio Campaign.
- I hold a driving license for class BCE

REFEREES UPON REQUEST